how to practice noble silence by not
engaging in any distracting behavior by
practicing wakefulness
so anything that you discern that it's
rooted in an unnecessary this desire to
distract yourself to take your mind away
from your present situation in your mind
flaw that's basically against the practice of
that's basically against the practice of
wakefulness but it's also supported to
note it's not like you don't need to be
forcing you might not come present and
present because you're present whether
you want it to be or not it's not option
it's not an option it's an optional loss
of mindfulness loss of wakefulness all
these things are rooted in basically
unwholesome intentions which means you
cannot become unweight for non wakeful
if you don't engage in any intentional
act based upon greed aversion delusion
save the mind minds intentions are not
rooted in any of you and also things
that you cannot be ungrateful and that's
already in noble silence you're not
distracted this mean you never speak to
anyone or you never like do anything
whatsoever no you just don't do things
that are rooted in desire of like greed
aversion or distraction and delusion
why is it silence because the mind
quiets down when the mind is distracted
the thoughts the verbal thoughts that
kind of dialect it's going on but once
you haven't been and again people drama
stop this thinking well you can't stop
the thinking you can quiet it down by
seeing basically the thinking the loud
thinking so to speak is a symptom of
your lack of your proper restraint not
restraining your mind in a proper manner
in a sense of not delighting in in in
lust aversion and delusion resisting
delusion the resisting the version and
again and engaging in distraction and
delusion but if you start discerning
that that's what quiets the mind down
you can are my mind quiet I focus on my
nostrils and I'll be quiet
no you just fall asleep most likely or
going some state of like focused
attention or to something well again we
just lost awareness and mindfulness
completely so you want to see basically
that the problem is not in you not
trying hard enough to be in the present
moment which is again not a matter of choice
which is again not a matter of choice
the problem is you not understanding the
nature of intentions you know but not
understanding you don't know when they
are rooted in greed or aversion of
delusion no idea you know you're just
guessing sometimes it gives you right
sometimes you don't but you don't see
that which means
so the mind will quiet down when the
physical restraint and seal has been
developed the verbal you know verbal
actions are kept in check and then
mentally you just don't give don't give
in to the like presented options of
sensuality or an aversion or distraction
if you don't just don't give it to those
if they are not those that's fine you
don't have to be honest be mindful know
you are already mindful by not giving in
you're already mindfully mindful because
you're already abstaining from certain
types of mental intention which are the
unwholesome types so basically things
you don't do that's what becomes your
present activity in that negative sense
that's why it's not on the level of
doing or on the level of technique you
can't be doing the abstaining from this
thing there is just discerning certain
things that you won't be giving into it
then everything else that's not those
things that's fine
that's why the Buddha moment he was sort
of instructing Minds how to understand
the John and stablish the money John he
would say he was at anything don't the
dalek feared every pleasant experience
because they had the attitude of
whatever is pleasant is a problem it is
it's a it's it's it should be it should
be dismissed so they were interfering
with things they shouldn't have because
if it's agreeable and not to do to the
desire aversion delusion it's not a
problem and you assuming they that
should go away well it's you
overstepping your jurisdiction you
interfering with that which is not yours
so some people might think that's
locking themselves into a situation of
solitude you know no distractions no TV
speed like a prisoner basically made to
general so so she's sort of in it so
achieved solitary confinement but most
people in that situation go mad yeah
yeah no no it's not like that's like
again if a person knows what they're
doing as in they understand the nature
they can discern the nature of their
that indirectly the nature of their
intentions they can see when they are
rooted then yes solitude will just
result in further clarity that's why the
Buddha would encourage monks provided
already had the right view and
establishment in sila in the strength to
go into in the jungle of the mud willing
to not socialize even with other marks
and so on but if you don't have that
knowledge then well again you might sort
of use it while keeping an ocean in your
mind that you must develop knowledge but
sometimes people forget that and then
they try to get the circumstances to do
the work for them so then I'll go for a
three-month retreat to burn minor cootie
and people who just bring me food
everyone won't see anyone and so on
thinking that that kind of extreme
solitude will sort of result in in in
freedom in life but you want you can
only support the knowledge if you don't
have the knowledge that's it you're just
staying in the solitude and you will not
necessarily learn from it because if
there were if the solid she would always
resulting then yes exactly that solitary
confinement prisoners will all be
adamant ceramics
there's been away from the
constellations well it's knowledge of the what
well it's knowledge of the what
defilements are and unwholesome
attention that's what frees you being
away from them is necessary to an extent
to start discerning that knowledge but
if you have no notion of what that
knowledge is no man have been being away
from those departments will have proven
if anything if you just concealment
further because now you don't really
don't know where to look for them
because before there were things kind of
they would sort of prop the issues up
for you and then you would see that
issues are still there and that's how
you could judge your work but in a
completely solitary confinement without
that prior knowledge now you really
don't know where to look
to give you strength building the
necessary basis there is strength in the
necessary basis yeah and usage of
solitude to use it to gain the knowledge
not to use it to avoid the circumstances
they bother you and you don't know how
to deal with